<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Shiva Saxena - misc</title><link href="https://geekyshacklebolt.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://geekyshacklebolt.github.io/feeds/misc.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://geekyshacklebolt.github.io/</id><updated>2020-02-13T21:07:00+05:30</updated><subtitle>Blog</subtitle><entry><title>Dotfiles Setup Initiated!</title><link href="https://geekyshacklebolt.github.io/dotfile-setup-initiated.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-02-13T21:07:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-02-13T21:07:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Shiva Saxena</name></author><id>tag:geekyshacklebolt.github.io,2020-02-13:/dotfile-setup-initiated.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recently, I initiated my dotfiles setup. And still, it is not fully furshined. I'll keep updating it as per my requirements and this blog post is here to share the same.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Greetings!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I initiated my dotfiles setup. And still, it is not fully furshined. I'll keep updating it as per my requirements and this blog post is here to share the same. My dotfiles are available on &lt;a href="https://github.com/geekyshacklebolt/dotfiles"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. In case, you don't know about dotfiles. Let me quickly wrap that up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What are dotfiles?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are actally configuration files of your systems, including all your tweaks that you did in your tools, all installed packages details, your specific customizations, etc. So, in case you change your machine or in case of hard-disk failures or in any case when you need to switch to other machine. Now running the installation of your dotfiles setup over the new machine will bring back all your configurations back. And that's the beauty of having a dotfiles setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Know more about dotfiles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read my detailed blog post on: &lt;a href="https://www.thegeekyway.com/what-are-dotfiles"&gt;What are Dotfiles?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can also get a lot of useful info. about dotfiles here: &lt;a href="https://github.com/webpro/awesome-dotfiles"&gt;Awesome-dotfiles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Switching machine is no more a headache when you have a working dotfiles setup, but make sure to keep updating your dotfiles repo with changes you do locally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you in the next post :)&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Getting Started With Pelican</title><link href="https://geekyshacklebolt.github.io/getting-started-with-pelican.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-02-05T20:28:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-02-05T20:28:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Shiva Saxena</name></author><id>tag:geekyshacklebolt.github.io,2020-02-05:/getting-started-with-pelican.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello Pelican! I'm super excited to start my personal blog. Because although I've been blogging for a period of time but I always wanted to have a blog with full control on frontend/backend and the one I can call as personal.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Greetings!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting a new blog mostly considered with HOW-TOs, detailed descriptions, product reviews, project documentation, monetization, marketing, etc. That means, most of the time people misunderstand the real purpose of blogging. For all those who would like to know why they should start a blog, kindly refer to &lt;a href="https://summertraining.readthedocs.io/en/latest/blogging.html"&gt;Why Blogging?&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been blogging for a few years. My previous blog is &lt;a href="https://geekyshacklebolt.wordpress.com"&gt;A Habit of Learning&lt;/a&gt; that is on wordpress. And I also contributed some technical tutorials on &lt;a href="https://www.thegeekyway.com/author/geekyshacklebolt"&gt;TheGeekyWay.com&lt;/a&gt;. But this one is going to be different. This one with pelican would be my personal blog from now on. I'll be sharing here my experience, etc. And with this, I am thinking of keeping this post short :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading.
See you in the next post! :)&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry></feed>